<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>𝓣𝓱𝓪𝓷𝓱.𝓫𝓮</title>
    <description>Progress with quality</description>
    <link>thanh.be/</link>
    <atom:link href="thanh.be/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 22:31:08 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 22:31:08 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tổng hợp posts về chạy bộ</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;tôi-nói-gì-khi-tôi-nói-về-chạy-bộ---my-version&quot;&gt;Tôi nói gì khi tôi nói về chạy bộ - my version&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tôi bắt đầu với chạy bộ một cách nghiêm túc chắc từ năm 2016 - cùng với game Pokemon Go. Không cheat nên tôi ra ngoài nhiều hơn và để tiết kiệm thời gian thì tôi chạy rồi dừng để bắt pokemon và xoay pokestop. Rồi dần dần tôi chạy dài hơn và bắt đầu nghiêm túc mua giày, áo tập. Tôi bắt đầu thử sức các giải chạy cự ly trung bình 20km Brussels và chạy trail 20km ở Spa. Đến tháng 10-2017, tôi tham gia Brussels Marathon - về đích trước cut-off time khoảng 5 phút, tôi là người thứ 7 từ dưới lên với thành tích 5h 25 phút và dính chấn thương ITband khá nặng ở chân trái. Lỗi là ở tôi không thay đôi giày chạy duy nhất sau hơn 1 năm và đôi giày đó hoàn toàn không phải để chạy cự ly marathon hay thậm chí half-marathon (đội Kalenji giá 10eu hoặc 15eu). Sau cự ly FM đầu tiên, dù chấn thương tôi vẫn tham gia giải chạy trail owr Spa cự ly 33km và cũng về đích sau cỡ 5 tiếng và chấn thương tồi tệ hơn. Tôi không thể nào chạy được quá 2km nữa và phải nghỉ hơn 1 năm. Sang năm 2019, tôi bắt đầu tập luyện một cách nghiêm túc hơn để ý đến tập luyện, giày dép, dáng chạy, dinh dưỡng và thành tích cải thiện đáng kể. Dù không tham gia giải nào ngoài các cự ly ngắn ở địa phương cho vui, tôi cũng có được PR khá tốt. Mục tiêu hướng đến của tôi là FM sub 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dành nhiều thời gian để tự nghiên cứu và áp dụng nhiều kiến thức về chạy bộ, tôi thấy mình cần phải hệ thống lại để tránh quên và chia sẻ cho người khác khi cần đến. Đó là lý do, tôi bắt đầu tổng hợp các kiến thức về chạy bộ ở blog này. Các vấn đề xung quanh chạy bộ được chia làm 4 nhóm: Tập luyện và Kỹ thuật - Nghỉ ngơi, Hồi phục và Dinh dưỡng - Giày và phụ kiện - Chấn thương&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tập-luyện-và-kỹ-thuật&quot;&gt;Tập luyện và kỹ thuật&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;giáo-án&quot;&gt;Giáo án&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kỹ-thuật-trong-chạy-bộ&quot;&gt;Kỹ thuật trong chạy bộ&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;các-bài-tập-bổ-trợ&quot;&gt;Các bài tập bổ trợ&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nghỉ-ngơi-hồi-phục-và-dinh-dưỡng&quot;&gt;Nghỉ ngơi, Hồi phục và Dinh Dưỡng&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nghỉ-ngơi&quot;&gt;Nghỉ ngơi&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hồi-phục&quot;&gt;Hồi phục&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dinh-dưỡng&quot;&gt;Dinh Dưỡng&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dinh-dưỡng-hàng-ngày-cho-vận-động-viên&quot;&gt;Dinh dưỡng hàng ngày cho vận động viên&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dinh-dưỡng-cho-cuộc-đua&quot;&gt;Dinh dưỡng cho cuộc đua&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;giày-và-phụ-kiện&quot;&gt;Giày và phụ kiện&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;giày-chạy&quot;&gt;Giày chạy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;đồng-hồ&quot;&gt;Đồng hồ&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;các-phụ-kiện-khác&quot;&gt;Các phụ kiện khác&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chấn-thương&quot;&gt;Chấn thương&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>thanh.be/run-index/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">thanh.be/run-index/</guid>
        
        <category>index</category>
        
        <category>running</category>
        
        <category>overview</category>
        
        
        <category>run</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Practice của Seth Godin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Công việc sáng tạo là hành động hào phóng có chủ đích làm mọi thứ tốt đẹp hơn bằng cách làm điều chưa chắc đã là đúng đắn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mỗi ngày chúng ta đối mặt với lựa chọn: sáng tạo &lt;strong&gt;be creative&lt;/strong&gt; HOẶC đầu hàng trước sự sợ hãi hoặc không chủ đích và trở thành &lt;strong&gt;hack&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;hustler&lt;/strong&gt; hoặc &lt;strong&gt;cog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hack&lt;/strong&gt; là sợ hãi thử cái mới, chỉ chăm chăm copy những thứ đã có sẵn mà không phát triển thêm lên&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hustler&lt;/strong&gt; chỉ quan tâm đến việc hoàn thành mục tiêu ngắn hạn hơn là tạo ra giá trị. Hustler có sự dũng cảm nhất định để thử các thứ không chắc là đúng nhưng chỉ cho các mục đích cá nhân.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cog&lt;/strong&gt; thường rất hào phóng nhưng chỉ thoải mái khi làm theo chỉ dẫn. Cog làm việc bó trong 1 system và không có ý định cải tiến nó. Khi thế giới thay đổi, hệ thống - system - cần được cập nhật, cog sẽ bị bỏ lại hoặc thay thế&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Khi bạn chọn con đường sáng tạo bằng cách rộng rãi và can đảm trong công việc của mình, bạn tạo cho mình một tiếng nói duy nhất, là người tiên phong trong công việc và tạo ra thay đổi có ý nghĩa. &lt;strong&gt;Nhưng chú ý:&lt;/strong&gt; khi bạn chọn con đường sáng tạo, bạn sẽ cảm thấy như mình là kẻ giả mạo (&lt;em&gt;imposter&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;impostor-syndrome---hội-chứng-sợ-giả-mạo&quot;&gt;Impostor Syndrome - Hội chứng sợ giả mạo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Khi bạn thử làm gì đó mới với hi vọng sẽ làm tốt hơn và thay đổi điều gì đó, bạn tất yếu phải cảm thấy là bạn chẳng biết mình đang làm cái quái gì, và luôn có cảm giá thường trực là bạn đang bị phán xét bởi người khác, và nghĩ: “&lt;em&gt;Mình chỉ là thằng lừa đảo&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nhưng trước khi bạn để giọng nói sợ hãi trong con người bạn lên quyết định và đầu hàng, bạn nên biết rằng tất cả mọi lãnh tụ chiến đấu cho lý tưởng, mọi nghệ sĩ đưa tác phẩm ra thế giới, mọi doanh nhân cố gắng bán được món hàng đầu tiên của mình, đều có chung cảm giác như bạn. Seth Godin nói trong tác phẩm của mình: “&lt;strong&gt;Sự sợ hãi trước điều giả mạo&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;imposter&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;strong&gt;là bằng chứng rằng chúng ta đang cải tiến, dẫn lối và sáng tạo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hãy dừng sự sợ hãi trước điều giả mạo đó giết chết động lực sáng tạo của bạn bằng cách cam kết 1 tiếng mỗi ngày cho hoạt động sáng tạo. Thói quen hình thành sẽ gỡ bỏ rào cản tâm lý.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-practice---thực-hành&quot;&gt;The Practice - Thực hành&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Việc thực hành sáng tạo của bạn có thể là viết lách, lập trình, vẽ, ghi podcasts, huấn luyện hay nấu ăn. Không phụ thuộc vào việc bạn làm trong lúc thực hành, mục tiêu chỉ có một: đừng chú ý đến kết quả, học cách yêu thích quá trình tạo ra nó. Càng trân trọng quá trình, bạn càng &lt;strong&gt;tin tưởng vào bản thân&lt;/strong&gt; để nhận thêm 1 chút rủi ro và kiên trì tạo ra thêm các sáng tạo mới, bất chấp cảm giác của một &lt;em&gt;imposter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Thực hành không có nghĩa là để đạt tới kết quả nào, thực hành bản thân nó là kết quả, bởi vì chỉ có sự thực hành là tất cả những gì chúng ta có thể điều khiển và kiểm soát được”&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bạn có thể thắc mắc: &lt;em&gt;“Nếu không tập trung vào kết quả, làm sao chúng ta biết được chúng ta có tiến bộ hay không?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Đo đếm sự tiến bộ của bằng hai đơn vị đo lương: &lt;strong&gt;discard pile - đống ý tưởng bỏ đi của bạn lớn từng nào&lt;/strong&gt; và &lt;strong&gt;bạn đã ship được bao nhiêu việc năm vừa rồi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;grow-your-discard-pile---đống-ý-tưởng-bỏ-đi-phải-cao-hơn-nữa&quot;&gt;Grow your discard pile - Đống ý tưởng bỏ đi phải cao hơn nữa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Ý tưởng tốt chỉ có thể đến sau nhưng ý tưởng tồi, nhưng nó chỉ đến khi bạn đã có đủ nhiều ý tưởng tồi” - Seth Godin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nếu bạn chẳng dám đưa ra ý tưởng, bạn chắc chắn không có ý tưởng tồi nào, và cũng chẳng có ý tưởng tốt nào chứ đừng nói đến ý tưởng thành công.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Đống ý tưởng giấy lộn có thể là vài dòng codes chẳng chạy như bạn mong muốn, ý tưởng về sản phẩm không thể tạo ra lãi, trò đùa mà chẳng ai cười, design mới mà chẳng ai buồn share hay bài thuyết trình công phu mà chẳng động tới tim ai cả. Nhưng không có chúng bạn sẽ chẳng có đủ kinh nghiệm, bài học, để ra đời những ý tưởng bớt tồi hơn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ship-more-on-schedule---hoàn-thành-nhiều-công-việc-hơn-và-đúng-tiến-độ&quot;&gt;Ship more, on schedule - Hoàn thành nhiều công việc hơn, và đúng tiến độ&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Chúng ta hoàn thành công việc chẳng phải vì chúng ta sáng tạo, chúng ta sáng tạo bởi vì chúng ta hoàn thành công việc” - Seth Godin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hoàn thành công việc được giao đúng lịch trình, bất chấp bạn cảm thấy nó thế nào. Hoàn thành công việc là nguyên tắc bạn cần tạo cho mình, không phải lựa chọn - vì bạn muốn hay không. Nói rõ “&lt;em&gt;Tôi sẽ hoàn thành &lt;strong&gt;___ mỗi __&lt;/strong&gt;_. Đó là cam kết của tôi, công việc của tôi&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bản thân Seth Godin hoàn thành 1 blog post cho độc giả mỗi ngày. Đó là cam kết của ông và cũng là công việc của ông.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chắc chắn sẽ có những ngày bạn chẳng muốn hoàn thành hoặc tin là công việc bạn hoàn thành chẳng có tý chất lượng nào. Tuy nhiên, chất lượng công việc chỉ có thể tốt lên khi nó được hoàn thành, và điều đó sẽ tạo ra cho bạn năng lượng sáng tạo mới để hoàn thành tốt hơn các công việc tiếp theo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mỗi lần hoàn thành công việc theo lịch trình định sẵn là cơ hội cho bạn cải tiến, phát triển nó tốt hơn so với công việc trước đó. Bằng việc liên tục cải tiến, bạn tự phát triển cho mình năng lực mới, tạo cho mình xúc giác mới để nhận viết được nên tập trung vào đâu để tạo điểm nhấn trong sản phẩm. Bắt đầu bằng việc hoàn thành và ship cho những người xung quanh (gia đình, bạn bè). Chỉ nên nhận những rủi ro trong sáng tạo mà bạn có khả năng chấp nhận được. Cùng với thời gian, năng lực và taste của bạn được phát triển hơn, bạn sẽ tìm đủ can đảm để ship sản phẩm của mình đến nhiều người hơn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kết-luận&quot;&gt;Kết luận&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bằng việc học cách yêu lấy quá trình sáng tạo, chồng cao hơn đống ý tưởng bỏ đi, ship sản phảm của mình thường xuyên hơn, bạn sẽ tạo được sản phẩm mang chất riêng và làm tốt hơn điều mình muốn làm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Tốt hơn lên là hoàn toàn có thể, nhưng chúng ta sẽ chẳng bao giờ đạt được nếu chúng ta chấp nhận ổn định, tiếp tục giấu khả năng của mình và chấp nhận đi đi đi lại con đường đã cũ. Chúng ta có nhiều thứ để làm, và chúng ta cần đóng góp. Nhưng điều đó chẳng thể hoặc mãi không xảy ra nếu chúng ta không tự tìm cách để tin tưởng bản thân mình đủ để can đảm làm công việc của mình” - Seth Godin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>thanh.be/book-the-practice/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">thanh.be/book-the-practice/</guid>
        
        <category>productivity</category>
        
        <category>book</category>
        
        <category>creative</category>
        
        
        <category>read</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor. If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-formatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;strike through&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;==highlight==&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-code-blocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;html&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;ml-1 mr-1&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;target=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;_blank&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;#&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;fab fa-twitter&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;css&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-css highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.highlight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.c&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#999988&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;font-style&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;italic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.highlight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#a61717&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#e3d2d2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;js&quot;&gt;JS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-js highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// alertbar later&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;scroll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;scrollTop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;280&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;.alertbar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;fadeIn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;.alertbar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;fadeOut&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;python&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello World&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;redcarpet&apos;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;markdown&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Redcarpet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello World!&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;markdown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;to_html&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;c&quot;&gt;C&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-c highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;printf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello World&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference-lists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick brown jumped over the lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-html&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>thanh.be/powerful-things-markdown-editor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">thanh.be/powerful-things-markdown-editor/</guid>
        
        
        <category>run</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>thanh.be/first-mass-produced/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">thanh.be/first-mass-produced/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Education must also train one for quick, resolute and effective thinking.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-formatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;strike through&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;==highlight==&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-code-blocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Rouge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference-lists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick brown jumped over the lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-html&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>thanh.be/education/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">thanh.be/education/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Accumulated experience of social living</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>thanh.be/acumulated-experience/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">thanh.be/acumulated-experience/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>About Bundler</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gem install bundler&lt;/code&gt; installs the bundler gem through RubyGems. You only need to install it once - not every time you create a new Jekyll project. Here are some additional details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundler&lt;/code&gt; is a gem that manages other Ruby gems. It makes sure your gems and gem versions are compatible, and that you have all necessary dependencies each gem requires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Gemfile&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Gemfile.lock&lt;/code&gt; files inform &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bundler&lt;/code&gt; about the gem requirements in your site. If your site doesn’t have these Gemfiles, you can omit &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle exec&lt;/code&gt; and just &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;run jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle exec jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bundler&lt;/code&gt; uses the gems and versions as specified in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Gemfile.lock&lt;/code&gt; to ensure your Jekyll site builds with no compatibility or dependency conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about how to use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bundler&lt;/code&gt; in your Jekyll project, this tutorial should provide answers to the most common questions and explain how to get up and running quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>thanh.be/about-bundler/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">thanh.be/about-bundler/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We all wait for summer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I engage in the so-called “bull sessions” around and about the school, I too often find that most college men have a misconception of the purpose of education. Most of the “brethren” think that education should equip them with the proper instruments of exploitation so that they can forever trample over the masses. Still others think that education should furnish them with noble ends rather than means to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that education has a two-fold function to perform in the life of man and in society: the one is utility and the other is culture. Education must enable a man to become more efficient, to achieve with increasing facility the ligitimate goals of his life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>thanh.be/we-all-wait-for-summer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">thanh.be/we-all-wait-for-summer/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tree of Codes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original — which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother — is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>thanh.be/tree-of-codes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">thanh.be/tree-of-codes/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Red Riding Hood</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original — which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother — is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>thanh.be/red-riding/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">thanh.be/red-riding/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
